I was on a long road trip this summer,
هذا الصيف، كنت في رحلة برية طويلة
and I was having a wonderful time listening
وكنت أحظى بوقت ممتع أستمع فيه إلى
to the amazing Isabel Wilkerson's "The Warmth of Other Suns."
رائعة إيزابيل وِلكرسون "ذا ورمث أوف أذر سنز."
It documents six million black folks fleeing the South from 1915 to 1970
إنها توثق هروب ستة ملايين من السود من الجنوب من عام 1915 وحتى 1970
looking for a respite from all the brutality
بحثًا عن راحة من كل الأعمال الوحشية
and trying to get to a better opportunity up North,
في محاولة للحصول على فرصة أفضل في الشمال،
and it was filled with stories of the resilience and the brilliance
وكانت الرواية مملوءة بقصص النباهة والذكاء
of African-Americans,
عند الأمريكيين الأفارقة،
and it was also really hard to hear all the stories of the horrors
وكان حقًا من الصعب الاستماع إلى كل قصص الرعب
and the humility, and all the humiliations.
والذل وكل الإهانات.
It was especially hard to hear about the beatings and the burnings
وخصوصًا كان يصعب الاستماع إلى الضرب والحرق
and the lynchings of black men.
والإعدام دون محاكمة بحق الرجال السود.
And I said, "You know, this is a little deep.
وقلت، "تعلمون، هذا عميق قليلًا.
I need a break. I'm going to turn on the radio."
أحتاج للراحة. سأشغل الراديو."
I turned it on, and there it was:
وشغلته، وكان التالي:
Ferguson, Missouri,
فيرغسون، ميزوري،
Michael Brown,
مايكل برون،
18-year-old black man,
رجل أسود في الثامنة عشرة من عمره،
unarmed, shot by a white police officer, laid on the ground dead,
غير مسلح، أُطلق عليه النار على يد شرطي أبيض، وقع جثة هامدة،
blood running for four hours
يسيل الدم لأربع ساعات
while his grandmother and little children and his neighbors watched in horror,
بينما تشاهده الجدة والأطفال الصغار وجيرانه في حالة من الهلع،
and I thought,
وفكرت،
here it is again.
ها هو مجددا.
This violence, this brutality against black men
هذا العنف وهذه الوحشية تجاه الرجال السود
has been going on for centuries.
قد استمرت على مدى قرون من الزمان.
I mean, it's the same story. It's just different names.
أعني، إنها نفس القصة ولكن بأسماء مختلفة.
It could have been Amadou Diallo.
كان يمكن أن يكون أمادو ديالو.
It could have been Sean Bell.
كان يمكن أن يكون شين بيل.
It could have been Oscar Grant.
كان يمكن أن يكون أوسكار غرانت.
It could have been Trayvon Martin.
كان يمكن أن يكون ترايفن مارتن.
This violence, this brutality,
هذا العنف وهذه الوحشية
is really something that's part of our national psyche.
هي حقًا شيء يمثل جزء من عقليتنا الوطنية.
It's part of our collective history.
إنها جزءٌ من تاريخنا الجماعي.
What are we going to do about it?
ماذا سنفعل حيالها؟
You know that part of us that still crosses the street,
تعلمون ذلك الجزء منا الذي لا زال يعبر الشارع
locks the doors,
ويقفل الأبواب
clutches the purses,
ويتمسّك بالمحفظة
when we see young black men?
عندما نرى الشباب السود؟
That part.
ذلك الجزء.
I mean, I know we're not shooting people down in the street,
أعني، أعلم أننا لا نطلق النار على الأشخاص في الطرقات،
but I'm saying that the same stereotypes and prejudices
ولكنني أقول بأن نفس الصور النمطية والأحكام المسبقة
that fuel those kinds of tragic incidents
التي تغذي كل أنواع الحوداث المأساوية
are in us.
موجودة فينا.
We've been schooled in them as well.
لقد تم تعليمنا إياها أيضًا.
I believe that we can stop these types of incidents,
أعتقد أن بإمكاننا وقف هذه الأنواع من الحوادث المؤسفة،
these Fergusons from happening,
وقف قتل الرجال من أمثال فرغسون،
by looking within and being willing to change ourselves.
بالنظر إلى دواخلنا وأن نكون على استعداد لتغيير أنفسنا.
So I have a call to action for you.
لذا فأنا أحمل دعوة لكم للقيام بشيء ما.
There are three things that I want to offer us today to think about
هناك ثلاثة أشياء أود عرضها علينا اليوم كي نفكر فيها
as ways to stop Ferguson from happening again;
كطرق لمنع تكرار حادثة فيرغسون مرة أخرى:
three things that I think will help us
ثلاثة أشياء أعتقد أنها ستساعدنا
reform our images of young black men;
على إعادة تشكيل تخيلاتنا عن الشباب السود؛
three things that I'm hoping will not only protect them
ثلاثة أشياء آمل ألا تساعدهم فحسب
but will open the world so that they can thrive.
بل أن تفتح أمامهم العالم كي يزدهروا.
Can you imagine that?
هل بإمكانك تخيل ذلك؟
Can you imagine our country embracing young black men,
هل بإمكانكم تخيل دولتنا تحتضن الشباب السود
seeing them as part of our future, giving them that kind of openness,
وتراهم كجزء من مستقبلنا وتعطيهم ذلك النوع من الانفتاح،
that kind of grace we give to people we love?
ذلك النوع من الحنان الذي نعطيه لأحبابنا؟
How much better would our lives be? How much better would our country be?
كم ستكون حياتنا أفضل؟ كم ستكون بلادنا أفضل؟
Let me just start with number one.
دعوني فقط أبدأ برقم واحد.
We gotta get out of denial.
علينا أن نخرج من دائرة الإنكار،
We need real people.
نحتاج أناسًا حقيقيين.
You know, I do a lot of diversity work,
تعلمون، أقوم بكثير من العمل في مجال التعددية،
and people will come up to me at the beginning of the workshop.
ويأتي الناس لي في بداية ورشة العمل.
They're like, "Oh, Ms. Diversity Lady, we're so glad you're here" --
كأنهم يقولون: "يا سيدة التعددية، نحن سعداء بكونك هنا" --
(Laughter) --
(ضحك) --
"but we don't have a biased bone in our body."
"ولكننا لا نملك عظمة منحازة في جسمنا."
And I'm like, "Really?
فأقول، "حقًا؟
Because I do this work every day, and I see all my biases."
لأنني أقوم بهذا العمل يوميًا وأرى كل انحيازاتي."
I mean, not too long ago, I was on a plane
أعني، مؤخرًا، كنت على متن طائرة
and I heard the voice of a woman pilot coming over the P.A. system,
وسمعت صوت قائدة الطائرة عبر مكبر الصوت
and I was just so excited, so thrilled.
وكنت متحمسة وسعيدةً جدًا.
I was like, "Yes, women, we are rocking it.
كنت كأنني أقول، "نعم يا امرأة، نحن نفعلها.
We are now in the stratosphere."
نحن الآن في الغلاف الجوي."
It was all good, and then it started getting turbulent and bumpy,
كل شيء كان جيدًا ومن ثم بدأ يصبح مضطربًا ومتخبطًا،
and I was like,
وكنت كأنني أقول،
"I hope she can drive."
"آمل أنها تستطيع القيادة."
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
I know. Right.
أعلم ذلك. صحيح.
But it's not even like I knew that was a bias
ولكن لم يكن الأمر وكأنني علمت بأنني منحازة
until I was coming back on the other leg and there's always a guy driving
حتى كنت أعود على الساق الأخرى ودائمًا ما كان هناك شابٌ يقود
and it's often turbulent and bumpy,
وتكون الطائرة غالبًا مضطربة ومتخبطة،
and I've never questioned the confidence of the male driver.
ولم يسبق لي أن شككت في الثقة بالسائق الذكر.
The pilot is good.
قائد الطائرة جيد.
Now, here's the problem.
الآن، هنا تكمن المشكلة.
If you ask me explicitly, I would say, "Female pilot: awesome."
إن سألتموني بصراحة، سأقول، "قائدة طائرة: شيء رائع."
But it appears that when things get funky and a little troublesome, a little risky,
ولكن يبدو أنه عندما تتحول الأشياء لتصبح غير تقليدية ومزعجة وخطيرة بعض الشيء،
I lean on a bias that I didn't even know that I had.
أميل إلى التحيز الذي لم أكن أعرف أنني امتلكته.
You know, fast-moving planes in the sky,
تعلمون، طائرات تتحرك بسرعة في السماء،
I want a guy.
أريد شابًا.
That's my default.
هذا هو وضعي الافتراضي.
Men are my default.
الرجال هم وضعي الافتراضي.
Who is your default?
من هو الافتراضي بالنسبة لك؟
Who do you trust?
من الذي تثق به؟
Who are you afraid of?
من الذي تخاف منه؟
Who do you implicitly feel connected to?
من الذي تشعر بالكامل أنك مرتبط به؟
Who do you run away from?
من الذي تهرب منه؟
I'm going to tell you what we have learned.
سأخبركم ماذا قد تعلمنا.
The implicit association test, which measures unconscious bias,
اختبار الارتباط الكامل، الذي يقيس انحياز العقل الباطن،
you can go online and take it.
بإمكانك أن تتصل بالإنترنت وتأخذه.
Five million people have taken it.
قد أخذه خمسة مليون شخص.
Turns out, our default is white. We like white people.
ويتضح، أن الافتراضي خاصتنا أبيض. نحب الناس البيض.
We prefer white. What do I mean by that?
نفضل البيض. ماذا أعني بذلك؟
When people are shown images of black men and white men,
عندما يُعرض على الناس صورٌ لرجال سود ورجال بيض،
we are more quickly able to associate
نحن أقدر وبسرعة أن نربط
that picture with a positive word, that white person with a positive word,
تلك الصورة مع كلمة إيجابية، الشخص الأبيض من كلمة إيجابية،
than we are when we are trying to associate
من أننا حين نحاول ربط
positive with a black face, and vice versa.
الإيجابي مع الوجه الأسود والعكس.
When we see a black face,
عندما نرى وجهًا أسود،
it is easier for us to connect black with negative
إنه من الأسهل لنا أن نربط الأسود مع السلبي
than it is white with negative.
مقارنة بربط الأبيض مع السلبي.
Seventy percent of white people taking that test prefer white.
سبعون بالمائة من الأشخاص البيض الذين يأخذون هذا الاختبار يفضلون البيض.
Fifty percent of black people
خمسون بالمائة من الأشخاص السود
You see, we were all outside when the contamination came down.
إذًا ترون، كنا جميعًا في الخارج عندما أتى التلوث.
What do we do about the fact that our brain automatically associates?
ما الذي يتوجب علينا فعله تجاه ما يرتبط به دماغنا بشكل أوتوماتيكي؟
You know, one of the things that you probably are thinking about,
تعلمون، إن أحد الأشياء التي يُحتمل أنكم تفكرون بشأنها،
and you're probably like, you know what,
وأنتم من المحتمل أنكم، تعلمون ماذا،
I'm just going to double down on my color blindness.
سأضاعف الرهان على عمى الألوان عندي.
Yes, I'm going to recommit to that.
نعم، سأسلم بذلك مرة أخرى.
I'm going to suggest to you, no.
سأقترح عليكم، لا.
We've gone about as far as we can go trying to make a difference
ذهبنا إلى الحد الذي نستطيع الذهاب إليه في محاولة لصنع فارق
trying to not see color.
في محاولة التغاضي عن رؤية اللون.
The problem was never that we saw color. It was what we did when we saw the color.
لم تكن المشكلة أبدًا في رؤيتنا للون. إنها كانت بما فعلناه عند رؤيتنا للون.
It's a false ideal.
إنه مفهوم خاطئ.
And while we're busy pretending not to see,
وبينما نحن مشغولون بالتظاهر بعدم الرؤية،
we are not being aware of the ways in which racial difference
لسنا ندرك الطرق التي تُغير من خلالها التفرقة العنصرية
is changing people's possibilities, that's keeping them from thriving,
إمكانيات الناس، التي تُبعدهم عن الازدهار،
and sometimes it's causing them an early death.
وفي بعض الأحيان تسبب لهم وفاة مبكرة.
So in fact, what the scientists are telling us is, no way.
لذا في الحقيقة، ما يخبرنا به العلماء هو، لا وسيلة.
Don't even think about color blindness.
لا تفكروا أبدًا بعمى الألوان.
In fact, what they're suggesting is,
في الحقيقة، ما يقترحونه هو،
stare at awesome black people.
حدقوا بالأشخاص السود الرائعين.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Look at them directly in their faces and memorize them,
انظروا إليهم مباشرة في عيونهم وتذكروهم،
because when we look at awesome folks who are black,
لأننا عندما ننظر إلى الناس الرائعين السود
it helps to dissociate
فذلك يساعد مباشرة على فصل الارتباط
the association that happens automatically in our brain.
الذي يحدث في أذهاننا.
Why do you think I'm showing you these beautiful black men behind me?
لماذا تعتقدون أني أريكم هؤلاء الرجال السود الجميلين من خلفي؟
There were so many, I had to cut them.
كان هناك الكثير منهم وتوجب عليّ قصهم.
Okay, so here's the thing:
حسنًا، هذا ما في الأمر:
I'm trying to reset your automatic associations about who black men are.
أحاول إعادة ضبط ربطكم الذهني الأوتوماتيكي حول ماهية الرجال السود.
I'm trying to remind you
أحاول تذكيركم
that young black men grow up to be amazing human beings
بأن الشباب السود كبروا ليكونوا بشرًا
who have changed our lives and made them better.
قد غيروا حياتنا إلى الأفضل.
So here's the thing.
إذًا ها هو الأمر.
The other possibility in science,
الاحتمال الآخر من ناحية علمية،
and it's only temporarily changing our automatic assumptions,
وهو يغير توقعاتنا الأوتوماتيكية بشكل مؤقت،
but one thing we know
ولكن من الجدير معرفته
is that if you take a white person who is odious that you know,
أنك إن أخذت شخصًا أبيض تعرفه بغيضا
and stick it up next to a person of color,
ووضعته بجانب شخص ملون،
a black person, who is fabulous,
شخص أسود رائع،
then that sometimes actually causes us to disassociate too.
ذلك في بعض الأحيان يسبب بالفعل فك ربط الذهني لدينا.
So think Jeffrey Dahmer and Colin Powell.
إذًا فكروا بجيفري داهمير وكولين بويل.
Just stare at them, right? (Laughter)
حدقوا بهم فقط، حسنًا؟ (ضحك)
But these are the things. So go looking for your bias.
ولكن هذه هي الأمور. إذًا فابحثوا عن انحيازكم.
Please, please, just get out of denial and go looking for disconfirming data
من فضلكم، من فضلكم اخرجوا فقط من الإنكار وابحثوا عن البيانات غير المؤكدة
that will prove that in fact your old stereotypes are wrong.
التي ستثبت بالفعل أن صوركم النمطية خاطئة.
Okay, so that's number one: number two,
حسنًا، إذًا كان ذلك رقم واحد: رقم اثنان،
what I'm going to say is move toward young black men instead of away from them.
ما أريد قوله هو أن تقدموا نحو الشباب السود بدلًا من الهروب منهم.
It's not the hardest thing to do,
إنه ليس بالشيء الصعب فعله،
but it's also one of these things
ولكنه أيضًا أحد هذه الأشياء
where you have to be conscious and intentional about it.
التي ينبغي عليكم أن تكونوا يقظين وإراديين بشأنها.
You know, I was in a Wall Street area one time several years ago
تعلمون، كنت ذات مرة في منطقة وول ستريت قبل عدة سنوات
when I was with a colleague of mine, and she's really wonderful
عندما كنت مع زميلة لي، وهي رائعة حقًا
and she does diversity work with me and she's a woman of color, she's Korean.
وهي تعمل معي في مجال التعددية وهي امرأة ملونة، إنها كورية.
And we were outside, it was late at night,
كنا في الخارج وكان الوقت متأخرًا في الليل،
and we were sort of wondering where we were going, we were lost.
كنا نوعًا ما نتساءل عن وجهتنا، كنا ضائعات.
And I saw this person across the street, and I was thinking, "Oh great, black guy."
ورأيت هذا الشخص في الشارع وكنت أفكر "عظيم، شاب أسود."
I was going toward him without even thinking about it.
كنت متجهة نحوه دون أدنى تفكير بذلك.
And she was like, "Oh, that's interesting."
وحالها كأنها تقول "ياه، هذا مدهش."
The guy across the street, he was a black guy.
هذا الشاب الذي في الشارع، كان شابًا أسود.
I think black guys generally know where they're going.
أعتقد أن الشباب السود بشكل عام يعرفون أين يذهبون.
I don't know why exactly I think that, but that's what I think.
لا أعلم لماذا بالضبط أعتقد ذلك، ولكن هذا ما أعتقده.
So she was saying, "Oh, you were going, 'Yay, a black guy'?"
إذًا فهي تقول أنني كنت أقول: "با لسعادتنا، شاب أسود؟"
She said, "I was going, 'Ooh, a black guy.'"
قالت "كنت أقول، 'أووه، شاب أسود'."
Other direction. Same need, same guy, same clothes,
الاتجاه الآخر. نفس الحاجة، نفس الشخص، نفس الملابس،
same time, same street, different reaction.
نفس الوقت، نفس الشارع، الاتجاه المعاكس.
And she said, "I feel so bad. I'm a diversity consultant.
وقالت "أشعر بالحزن الشديد، أنا مستشارة تعددية.
I did the black guy thing. I'm a woman of color. Oh my God!"
كررت السلوك الانحيازي. أنا امرأة أميز حسب اللون. يا إلهي!"
And I said, "You know what? Please. We really need to relax about this."
وقلتُ "أتعلمين؟ أرجوكِ نحتاج حقًا لأن نسترخي تجاه هذا.
I mean, you've got to realize I go way back with black guys.
أقصد، عليك أن تدركي بأن لي تاريخا مع الشباب السود.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
My dad is a black guy. You see what I'm saying?
أبي رجل أسود. تفهمين ما أقول؟
I've got a 6'5" black guy son. I was married to a black guy.
أملك ابنًا أسود طوله 6.5 إنشًا. كنت متزوجة من رجل أسود.
My black guy thing is so wide and so deep
موضوع الرجل الأسود عندي هو كبير جدًا وعميق جدًا
that I can pretty much sort and figure out who that black guy is,
حتى أنني أستطيع إلى حد كبير فرز وتحديد من كان ذلك الشاب الأسود،
and he was my black guy.
وهو كان الشاب الأسود خاصتي.
He said, "Yes, ladies, I know where you're going. I'll take you there."
قال "نعم، سيداتي، أعلم أين تذهبن. سآخذكم إلى هناك."
You know, biases are the stories we make up about people
تعلمون، إن الانحيازات هي قصص نخترعها عن الأشخاص
before we know who they actually are.
قبل أن نعرف حقيقتهم.
But how are we going to know who they are
ولكن كيف سنعرفهم
when we've been told to avoid and be afraid of them?
بينما تم إخبارنا باجتنابهم والخوف منهم؟
So I'm going to tell you to walk toward your discomfort.
حسنًا، سأقول لكم بأن تمضوا نحو ما لا يريحكم.
And I'm not asking you to take any crazy risks.
لا أطلب منكم ارتكاب مخاطر حمقاء.
I'm saying, just do an inventory,
أقول، اعملوا جردًا فحسب،
expand your social and professional circles.
قوموا بتوسيع دوائركم الاجتماعية والمهنية.
Who's in your circle?
مَن في دائرتكم؟
Who's missing?
من غير الموجود فيها؟
How many authentic relationships
كم عدد العلاقات الأصيلة
do you have with young black people, folks, men, women?
التي تملكونها مع أشخاص سود، شبابًا ورجالًا ونساء؟
Or any other major difference from who you are
أو أي اختلاف رئيسي مِن مَن أنتم
and how you roll, so to speak?
وكيف تتصرفون، مثلًا؟
Because, you know what? Just look around your periphery.
لأنكم، تعلمون؟ انظروا فقط من حولكم.
There may be somebody at work, in your classroom,
ربما يكون أحد ما في العمل، في الصف،
in your house of worship, somewhere, there's some black young guy there.
في مكان عبادتكم، في مكان ما، هناك بعض الشباب السود هناك.
And you're nice. You say hi.
وأنتم لطفاء. قولوا أهلًا.
I'm saying go deeper, closer, further, and build the kinds of relationships,
أقول لكم، اذهبوا أعمق وأقرب وأبعد وقوموا ببناء أنواع العلاقات،
the kinds of friendships that actually cause you to see the holistic person
أنواع العلاقات التي تدفعكم بالفعل إلى رؤية الشخص بأكمله
and to really go against the stereotypes.
وأن تقفوا ضد الصور النمطية.
I know some of you are out there,
أعرف أن بعضًا منكم موجودون،
I know because I have some white friends in particular that will say,
أعرف لأنني أمتلك أصدقاءً بيض سيقولون بالتحديد،
"You have no idea how awkward I am.
"ليس لديك أدنى فكرة عن حماقتي.
Like, I don't think this is going to work for me.
لا أعتقد بأن هذا سيصلح معي.
I'm sure I'm going to blow this."
متأكد بأنني سأخرب هذا."
Okay, maybe, but this thing is not about perfection. It's about connection.
حسنًا، ربما، ولكن هذا الشيء ليس عن المثالية. إنه عن الارتباط.
And you're not going to get comfortable before you get uncomfortable.
ولن تشعروا بالراحة قبل ألا تشعروا بها.
I mean, you just have to do it.
أقصد، عليكم أن تفعلوها فحسب.
And young black men, what I'm saying is
وللشباب السود، ما أقوله هو
if someone comes your way, genuinely and authentically, take the invitation.
إن أتى شخص ما في طريقكم بأصالة، فاقبلوا الدعوة.
Not everyone is out to get you.
ليس الجميع يسعون ضدكم.
Go looking for those people who can see your humanity.
اذهبوا للبحث عن هؤلاء الناس الذين يستطيعون رؤية إنسانيتكم.
You know, it's the empathy and the compassion
تعلمون، إنه التعاطف والرحمة
that comes out of having relationships with people who are different from you.
التي تأتي من امتلاك علاقات مع أشخاص مختلفين عنكم.
Something really powerful and beautiful happens:
يحدث شيء قوي وجميل:
you start to realize that they are you,
تبدؤون بإدراك أنهم أنتم،
that they are part of you, that they are you in your family,
أنهم جزء منكم، أنهم أنتم داخل أسرتكم،
and then we cease to be bystanders
ثم نتوقف عن كوننا متفرجين
and we become actors, we become advocates,
ونصبح ممثلين ونصبح مؤيدين
and we become allies.
ونصبح حلفاء.
So go away from your comfort into a bigger, brighter thing,
إذًا فاخرجوا من دائرة راحتكم إلى الشيء الأكبر والأكثر إشراقًا
because that is how we will stop another Ferguson from happening.
لأننا بهذه الطريقة سنمنع تكرار حادثة فيرغسون مرة أخرى.
That's how we create a community
هذه هي طريقة بنائنا لمجتمع
where everybody, especially young black men, can thrive.
حيث يستطيع كل شخص، وخصوصًا الشباب السود، الازدهار.
So this last thing is going to be harder,
إذًا هذا الشيء الأخير سيكون أصعب،
and I know it, but I'm just going to put it out there anyway.
وأعلم ذلك، ولكنني أحاول أن أظهرها لكم على أية حال.
When we see something, we have to have the courage to say something,
عندما نرى شيئًا ما، علينا أن نتحلى بالشجاعة لقول شيء ما،
even to the people we love.
حتى للأشخاص الذين نحبهم.
You know, it's holidays and it's going to be a time
تعلمون، إنها الأعياد وسيأتي الوقت
when we're sitting around the table and having a good time.
عندما نجلس حول الطاولة ونمضي وقتًا جميلًا.
Many of us, anyways, will be in holidays,
الكثير منا، على أية حال، سيكونون في الأعياد،
and you've got to listen to the conversations around the table.
وستستمعون إلى محادثات حول الطاولة.
You start to say things like, "Grandma's a bigot."
تبدؤون بقول أشياء مثل "جدتي متعصبة."
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
"Uncle Joe is racist."
"عمي جو عنصري."
And you know, we love Grandma and we love Uncle Joe. We do.
وتعلمون، نحب جدتنا ونحب العم جو. نحبهم.
We know they're good people, but what they're saying is wrong.
نعلم أنهم أشخاص جيدون، ولكن ما يقولونه خاطئ.
And we need to be able to say something, because you know who else is at the table?
ونحتاج لأن نكون قادرين على قول شيء ما لأنكم تعلمون من الآخرين على الطاولة؟
The children are at the table.
يجلس الأطفال على الطاولة.
And we wonder why these biases don't die, and move from generation to generation?
ونتساءل لماذا لا تكذب هذه الانحيازات وتنتقل من جيل إلى آخر؟
Because we're not saying anything.
لأننا لا نقول شيئًا.
We've got to be willing to say, "Grandma, we don't call people that anymore."
كان علينا أن نكون مستعدين لأن نقول "جدتي، لم نعد ننادي الأشخاص هكذا."
"Uncle Joe, it isn't true that he deserved that.
"عم جو، ليس صحيحًا أنه استحق ذلك.
No one deserves that."
لا أحد يستحق ذلك."
And we've got to be willing
وكان علينا أن نكون مستعدين
to not shelter our children from the ugliness of racism
لكيلا ندافع عن أبنائنا من بشاعة العنصرية
when black parents don't have the luxury to do so,
عندما لا يملك الآباء السود الإمكانية لفعل ذلك،
especially those who have young black sons.
خصوصًا أولئك الذين يملكون أبناءً سود.
We've got to take our lovely darlings, our future,
كان علينا أن نأخذ أعزاءنا المحبوبين، مستقبلنا،
and we've got to tell them we have an amazing country with incredible ideals,
وكان علينا أن نخبرهم بأننا نمتلك بلادًا جميلة بأفكار مدهشة،
we have worked incredibly hard, and we have made some progress,
لقد عملنا بجد بشكل لا يصدق، وقد حققنا بعض التقدم،
but we are not done.
ولكننا لم ننتهي.
We still have in us this old stuff
لا زال فينا هذا الشيء القديم
about superiority and it is causing us
عن التفوق وهذا يدفعنا إلى
to embed those further into our institutions
نقل هذا إلى حد أبعد في مؤسساتنا
and our society and generations,
وفي مجتمعنا وأجيالنا،
and it is making for despair
وهو سبب في كون اليأس
and disparities and a devastating devaluing of young black men.
والتباين والإحباط يحط من قدر الشباب السود.
We still struggle, you have to tell them,
لا زلنا نكافح، عليكم أن تقولوا لهم،
with seeing both the color
برؤية كل من اللون
and the character of young black men,
وشخصية الشباب السود،
but that you, and you expect them,
لكنكم أنتم، وأنتم من دونهم،
to be part of the forces of change in this society
ستكونون قوى التغيير في هذا المجتمع
that will stand against injustice and is willing, above all other things,
التي ستقف في وجه الظلم وتكونون مستعدين، قبل أي شيء آخر،
to make a society where young black men can be seen for all of who they are.
لصناعة مجتمع يمكن أن يتم رؤية الشباب السود فيه على حقيقتهم.
So many amazing black men,
إذًا فالعديد من الرجال السود الرائعين،
those who are the most amazing statesmen that have ever lived,
هؤلاء الذين هم أروع من عاشوا من رجال الدولة على الإطلاق،
brave soldiers,
جنود شجعان
awesome, hardworking laborers.
وعمال مجتهدون رائعون.
These are people who are powerful preachers.
هؤلاء الناس هم دعاة أقوياء.
They are incredible scientists and artists and writers.
هم علماء وفنانون وكتّاب مدهشون.
They are dynamic comedians.
هم كوميديون بطبيعتهم.
They are doting grandpas,
هم أجداد شغفون
caring sons.
وأبناء مهتمون.
They are strong fathers,
هم آباء أقوياء
and they are young men with dreams of their own.
وهم شباب يملكون أحلامهم الخاصة.
Thank you.
شكرًا لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)